♪Wind♪
♪ الرياح ♪
♪Incidentally blows away fascinating whispers of love♪
♪ يضرب عرضا بيادق الحب الرائعة ♪
♪Whispers of love♪
♪ حراس الحب ♪
♪Sound the best with loyalty to the only valentine♪
♪ دق أفضل بالولاء إلى الوصية الوحيدة ♪
♪The prosperous life♪
♪ الحياة المزدهرة ♪
♪Is when we are together all year round♪
♪ هو عندما نكون معا على مدار السنة ♪
♪For the rest of my life♪
♪ لبقية حياتي ♪
♪All I want is a perfect love with you♪
♪ كل ما أريد هو حبك المثالي ♪
♪I'll remain elegant for you all my life♪
♪ سأبقى أنيقة لك طوال حياتي ♪
♪Giving you my love little by little♪
♪ إعطائك حبي شيئًا فشيئًا ♪
♪I care for you with every piece of my heart♪
♪ أنا أهتم بك في كل قلبي ♪
♪And I miss you every day and night♪
♪ وأنا أشتاق إليك كل ليلة ♪
♪I'll be loyal to you in the best years of my life♪
♪ سأكون مخلصا لك في أفضل سنوات حياتي ♪
♪Melting love with gentle smiles♪
♪ تميّز الحب بالأعمدة الحمقاء ♪
♪I won't be afraid of anything♪
♪ لن أشعر بالخوف من أي شيء ♪
♪And I won't change my heart for you♪
♪ لن أغيّر قلبي من أجلك ♪
=Jade's Fateful Love=
= حب اليشم المؤلم =
=Episode 11=
= الحلقة 11 =
Hya.
هيا
Your Highness!
سموك!
Your Highness.
سموك
Are you all right?
هل أنت بخير
Confess.
اعترف
Who sent you?
من أرسلك؟
It's... It's the prefect.
إنه... إنه الولاء
The prefect's guard Xu Wei.
شو وي
(The West Market)
(السوق الغربية)
New cosmetics for sale.
مستحضرات التجميل الجديدة للبيع
Come have a look.
تعالوا وألقوا نظرة
Come on. Take a look.
هيا، ألق نظرة
Gentleman, you can get a good bargain.
أيها السيد، يمكنك الحصول على صفقة جيدة
What is this?
ما هذا؟
Good eye, gentleman.
العين الجيدة أيها الرجل النبيل
This is the compass.
هذه هي البوصلة
The stars, the five elements, and the sexagenary circle...
النجوم والعناصر الخمسة والدائرة القائمة على أساس الجنس
It can be used for anything mysterious.
يمكن استخدامها لأي شيء غامض
It's so magic.
إنه سحرية جدا
If I buy it for Yueling,
إذا اشتريته من أجل يونغ
she'll be happy.
ستكون سعيدة
I'll take it.
سآخذ ذلك
Thirty taels, please.
ثلاثون تايل، من فضلك
Thirty taels?
ثلاثون تايل؟
Too expensive.
باهظة الثمن
I won't take it, then.
لن آخذه إذًا
What price do you prefer?
ما هو الثمن الذي تفضلين؟
Five.
خمسة
Five?
خمسة؟
You...
أنت...
Even the cost is higher.
حتى التكلفة أعلى
I won't take it, then.
لن آخذه إذًا
Come on, gentleman.
بحقك، رجل نبيل
Fine, you can have it.
حسنًا، يمكنك الحصول عليها
Come more often to buy something from me.
تعالي في كثير من الأحيان لشراء شيء مني
Did I offer too much?
هل قدمت الكثير؟
I should have offered less.
كان يجب أن أعرض أقل
Thank you, gentleman. Welcome again.
شكرًا لك أيها اللطيف، أهلًا بك مجددًا
Someone's killed!
شخص ما قتل!
That female assassin.
تلك المرأة القاتل
- Go after her. - After her.
- اذهب وراءها - بعد هي
Where's she?
أين هي؟
How did she run so fast?
كيف ركضت بسرعة؟
(The House of Romance)
(بيت الرومانسية)
Hey, gentleman.
أيها السيد
Who's that?
من هذا؟
Su Nian, it's me.
سو نيان، هذا أنا
Mr. Xingyi, there you are.
السيد شينغ يي، ها أنت ذا
I'm here to see Su Nian.
أنا هنا لرؤية سو نيان
She's going to sleep.
سوف تنام
How about you come another day?
ما رأيك أن تأتي في يوم آخر؟
I have something urgent to ask her.
لدي شيء عاجل لأطرحه عليها
I can't wait.
لا أستطيع الانتظار
Mr. Xingyi.
السيد شينغ يي
Today on the West Market, I met the female assassin again.
في السوق الغربية، قابلت القاتل مرة أخرى
She escaped after she was injured.
هربت بعد أن أصيبت بجروح
I followed her all the way here.
تابعتها إلى هنا
You keep talking
أنت تستمر في التحدث
about the female assassin.
عن القاتل
I'm not interested in her.
أنا لست مهتما بها
It's getting late.
تأخر الوقت
I'm going to sleep.
سأنام
You should go back.
يجب أن تعود
You're injured.
أنت مصاب
You still think I'm the assassin?
هل ما زلت تعتقد أنني القاتل؟
I followed her here.
تابعتها هنا
Worried about you,
بدافع القلق عليك
I came in to check on you.
جئت للاطمئنان عليك
I've been learning a sword dance
لقد كنت أتعلم رقصة سيف
but always fail to master it.
ولكن دائما يفشل في السيطرة عليها
When I practiced just now, I was injured.
عندما تدربت للتو، أصبت بجروح
If you don't believe me
إذا كنت لا تصدّقني
and still suspect me,
ولا تزال تشك بي
go ask the guards to arrest me.
اذهب واطلب من الحراس للقبض عليّ
Oh, I see.
فهمت
Su Nian, how could you be so careless?
سو نيان، كيف لك أن تكوني مهملة جدا؟
Let me check your hand.
دعني أتحقق من يدك
Come and sit down.
تعالي واجلس
Let me apply some ointment for you.
دعني أضع لك بعض المرهم
This will make you feel better.
هذا سيجعلك تشعرين بتحسن
Oh, no.
لا
How have you been in Liuzhou lately?
كيف كنت في ليوتشو في الآونة الأخيرة؟
I lost my jade pendant for no reason.
فقدت قلادة اليشم بلا سبب
What about yours?
ماذا عن الخاصة بك؟
Everything's fine with me in the Capital City.
كل شيء على ما يُرام معي في العاصمة
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
This will sound normal.
سوف يبدو هذا طبيعيا
(How have you been in Liuzhou lately?)
(كيف كنت في ليوتشو مؤخرا؟)
(She didn't mention what happened in the palace.)
(لم تذكر ما حدث في القصر)
(How could everything be fine?)
(كيف يمكن أن يكون كل شيء على ما يرام؟)
Your Highness, we found the track
صاحب السمو، وجدنا المسار
of Mr. Shi Xuan near the West Hill.
من السيد شيوان بالقرب من تل الغرب
What about the twenty thousand dan of grain?
ماذا عن عشرين ألف طن من الحبوب؟
Hasn't been found yet.
لم يتم العثور عليها بعد
The grain can't disappear into thin air.
لا يمكن للحبوب أن تختفي في الهواء النقي
Nie Chen,
تشن
take another team
خذي فريقاً آخر
to search for the grain.
للبحث عن الحبوب
Yes.
نعم
But more refugees have come.
لكن المزيد من اللاجئين قد أتوا
The remaining grain can only last one day, I'm afraid.
باقي الحبوب لا يمكنها أن تدوم إلا يومًا واحدًا، أخشى أن يكون ذلك
Open my private barn and distribute my grain.
افتح حبيبتي الخاصة ووزع حبيبتي
Your Highness, isn't this inappropriate?
صاحب السمو، أليس هذا غير مناسب؟
People may suspect.
قد يشكك الناس
I can't care too much now.
لا أستطيع الاهتمام كثيرا الآن
I must give priority to the refugees.
يجب أن أعطي الأولوية للاجئين
I'm going to the West Hill to look for Shi Xuan.
أنا ذاهبة إلى غرب هيل للبحث عن شي
Maybe before we find him,
ربما قبل أن نجده
we will not know what exactly happened.
لن نعرف ما الذي حدث بالضبط
But Your Highness, your injury...
ولكن صاحب السمو، إصابتك...
It's all right.
لا بأس
(The North Prince's Mansion)
(قصر الأمير الشمالي)
Come on, Linmu.
هيا يا ليمو
Do you have nothing to do?
أليس لديك ما تفعلينه؟
My duty is to protect you and Her Highness.
واجبي هو حمايتك وحماية صاحبة السمو
I don't need your protection.
لست بحاجة إلى حمايتك
Qianqian.
تشيان
Your Grace.
غريسك
Has His Highness written back?
هل تراجع سموه؟
Not yet.
ليس بعد
Your Grace, a carrier pigeon.
عرشك، حمامة ناقلات
Is it from His Highness?
هل هي من سموه؟
His Highness was assassinated.
اغتيل سموه
(His Highness was assassinated in Liuzhou, but he was all right.)
(اغتيل سموه في ليوتشو، لكنه كان على ما يرام)
(His return journey will be postponed.)
(سيتم إرجاء رحلة عودته)
(Have our guards stay alert just in case.)
(اجعل حراسنا في حالة تأهب فقط)
Make way.
افسحوا الطريق
- Go search over there. - Yes.
- اذهب للبحث هناك - نعم
- You guys go there.
- اذهبا إلى هناك يا رفاق
General,
جنرال
what are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
This is the North Prince's mansion.
هذه هي قصر الأمير الشمالي
Your Grace,
غريسك
are you really going to Liuzhou?
هل ستذهب حقا إلى ليوتشو؟
Yes. He can't be safe unless we stay together.
نعم، لا يمكنه أن يكون آمنا ما لم نبق معا
Besiege them.
حصرهم
Imperial guards?
حراس إمبراطورية؟
Who allows you to besiege this mansion?
من يسمح لك بمحاصرة هذه القصر؟
Here's the decree from His Majesty.
ها هو مرسوم جلالة الإمبراطور
The North Prince wants to rebel.
أمير الشمال يريد التمرد
Everyone in his mansion will be grounded.
الجميع في قصره سيكون على قيد الحصر
None of them can leave.
لا يمكن لأحد منهم المغادرة
Rebel?
متمرد؟
(Hall of Politics)
(قاعة السياسة)
Your Majesty,
صاحبة الجلالة
the grain delivered to Liuzhou was gone for no reason.
الحبوب التي سلمت إلى ليوتشو جرت دون سبب
The North Prince suddenly had some grain.
أمسك الأمير الشمالي فجأة ببعض الحبوب
Having illegal iron mines and hoarding grain,
ومناجم الحديد غير المشروعة
it's so clear
من الواضح جدًا
that the North Prince wants to rebel.
أن الأمير الشمالي يريد التمرد
Prime Minister has a point.
رئيس الوزراء لديه نقطة
The North Prince had illegal iron mines
كان الأمير الشمالي يملك مناجم الحديد غير القانونية
and that showed his intention of rebellion.
وهذا يظهر عزمه على التمرد
Your Majesty, it was benevolent of you
جلالتك، كان خير لك
to punish him lightly.
لمعاقبته باستخفاف
Now, he has hoarded grain.
الآن، لقد قام بحراسة الحبوب على حسابه
Your Majesty, don't let him go
صاحب الجلالة، لا تدعه يذهب
just for the sake of your brotherhood.
فقط من أجل أخوتك
Shiyu is my brother.
شيو هو أخي
And he's using his grain on disaster relief.
وهو يستخدم حبيبه في الإغاثة من الكوارث
This case remains inconclusive.
لا تزال هذه القضية غير حاسمة
I need more time to find out the truth.
أحتاج إلى المزيد من الوقت لمعرفة الحقيقة
I think
أعتقد
this case is very clear.
هذه الحالة واضحة جدا
The North Prince is nowhere to be found.
الأمير الشمالي في أي مكان
It further proves something wrong.
إنه يثبت أيضا وجود شيء خاطئ
Even in this case,
حتى في هذه الحالة
there's no conclusive evidence
لا توجد أدلة قاطعة
to prove His Highness's treason.
لإثبات خيانة سموه
My fellow lords,
زملائي اللوردات
aren't you being too arbitrary?
ألا تتصرف بالتعسف الشديد؟
Your Majesty, as far as I see...
جلالتك، بقدر ما أرى...
Your Majesty.
جلالتك
An emperor must not be soft-hearted.
يجب ألا يكون الإمبراطور أقل قلب
What the North Prince did is obvious.
ما فعله الأمير الشمالي واضح
As his uncle,
وبصفتي عمه
I feel sorry for him with deep regret.
أشعر بالأسف الشديد عليه
But the national laws
لكن القوانين الوطنية
allow no favoritism.
لا تسمحي بأي خدمة
I've learned
لقد تعلمت
your different points.
نقاطك المختلفة
Now,
الآن
the North Prince's Mansion is sealed at the command of Prime Minister.
قصر الأمير الشمالي مغلق بإمرة رئيس الوزراء
I won't deal with the rest
لن أتعامل مع الباقي
before he's back to the Capital City.
قبل عودته إلى العاصمة
- Your Majesty, you... - I'm tired.
- صاحب الجلالة، أنت... - أنا متعب
Say no more about this.
لا مزيد من المعلومات عن هذا
His Majesty still can't make up his mind.
ما زال جلالة الإمبراطور لا يستطيع اتخاذ قرار
Let's take action.
دعنا نتخذ إجراء
Yes, Prime Minister.
نعم، رئيس الوزراء
(Benign and Benevolent)
(خير وخير)
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
I asked a familiar imperial guard
طلبت من الحارس الإمبراطوري المألوف
for some information.
لبعض المعلومات
He said, the twenty thousand dan of grain delivered to Liuzhou
قال، العشرين ألف طن من الحبوب التي سلمت إلى ليوتشو
was gone with Shi Xuan, the Minister of Revenue.
ذهب مع شيوان، وزير الإيرادات
His Highness took grain out of his private barn for the refugees.
أخذ سموه الحبوب من حلته الخاصة للاجئين
Isn't that a good thing?
أليس هذا أمرًا جيدًا؟
Why do they say he rebelled?
لماذا يقولون إنه تمرد؟
It is a good thing to feed the refugees.
إطعام اللاجئين أمر جيد
But the problem is His Highness used his private barn.
لكن المشكلة هي أن الأمير استخدم حنكته الخاصة
So, he was slandered for treason.
لذلك، تم تلطيفه بالخيانة
Where is he now?
أين هو الآن؟
Has he recovered?
هل تعافى؟
His Highness...
سموه...
He's missing.
إنه مفقود
Oh, no.
لا
I have to go there for him.
يجب أن أذهب إلى هناك من أجله
I must stay with him.
يجب أن أبقى معه
- Or he... - Your Highness,
- أم... - صاحب السمو
the whole mansion is besieged now.
القصر بأكمله محاصر الآن
I don't think we can go out.
لا أعتقد أننا نستطيع الخروج
Yeah, Yueling.
نعم، يوي ينغ
I just checked around.
راجعت فقط في كل مكان
Even the back door and the corners
حتى الباب الخلفي والزاوايا
are guarded by the imperial guards.
يحرسهم الحراس الإمبراطورية
What do we do?
ماذا نفعل؟
Oh, you're all here.
جميعكم هنا
I don't need to look for you everywhere.
لست بحاجة للبحث عنك في كل مكان
Your Highness?
صاحبة السمو؟
How did you get in?
كيف دخلت؟
It doesn't matter.
لا يهم
What matters is I'm here to see you.
ما الذي يهمني أن أراك هنا
See me?
أراني؟
Yeah. I'm here to see you.
نعم أنا هنا لرؤيتك
Now, Zhou Shiyu is in big trouble.
الآن، تشو شي يو في ورطة كبيرة
I don't think he can come back.
لا أعتقد أنه يستطيع العودة
Why don't you think about marrying someone else?
لماذا لا تفكر في الزواج من شخص آخر؟
Our prince is really charming.
أميرنا فاخر حقا
(Talent) Your Highness,
(موهبة) صاحب السمو
our prince isn't convicted yet.
أميرنا لم يتم إدانته بعد
What do you mean?
ماذا تعني؟
Yeah.
نعم
Her Grace will consider marrying anyone but you.
ستنظر في زواج أي شخص إلا أنت
You'd better leave now.
من الأفضل أن تخرج الآن
Or I can't help punching you.
أم لا أستطيع المساعدة في لكمك
Look.
انظر
Look at these shortsighted people.
انظروا إلى هؤلاء الناس قصيرة النظر
Under such circumstances,
وفي ظل هذه الظروف
you're still so ungrateful.
أنت لا تزال غير ممتن جدا
Your princess
أميرتك
can live a great life with me
يمكن أن تعيش حياة رائعة معي
and what's so bad about it?
وما السيئ في الأمر؟
If I go with you, I can leave here?
إذا ذهبت معك، يمكنني المغادرة هنا؟
Are you powerful enough?
هل أنت قوي بما فيه الكفاية؟
Funny.
مضحك
In the Capital City, who dares to stop me?
في العاصمة، من يجرؤ على إيقافي؟
Your Highness, think twice.
صاحب السمو، فكري مرتين
I can go with you.
يمكنني أن أذهب معك
But now I'm the North Princess Consort.
ولكن الآن أنا قرينة الأميرة الشمالية
If I go with you,
إذا ذهبت معك
shouldn't I first see His Majesty and get rid of the engagement?
ألا ينبغي أن أرى جلالة الملك أولا وأتخلص من الخطوبة؟
- Your Grace. - Yueling.
- غريسك - يليق بك
Don't do that.
لا تفعل ذلك
That's good.
هذا جيد
You should get rid of it.
يجب أن تخلصي منه
I'm taking you to His Majesty now.
سآخذك إلى جلالة الإمبراطور الآن
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
don't fall for it.
لا تقع في فخك
Your Grace.
غريسك
You're right.
أنت على حق
I'm going to the palace with you.
أنا ذاهبة إلى القصر معك
Your Grace.
عرشك
Your Grace, think before you go.
عرشك، فكر قبل أن تذهب
Yeah. His Highness is coming back soon.
نعم سموه سيعود قريبا
- Think more carefully. - Yueling, I don't agree.
- فكر بعناية أكثر - يويينغ، أنا لا أتفق
I've made up my mind.
لقد اتخذت قرار
I'll pick him.
سأختاره هو
You will?
حقًا؟
What are you waiting for? Let's go.
ماذا تنتظر؟ هيا بنا
- Your Grace. - Yueling.
- غريسك - يليق بك
All right.
حسنًا
Let's go.
لنذهب
- Yueling. - Your Grace.
- يليق بك - غرامك
Your Majesty,
صاحب الجلالة
Princess Ashina Zhu is here to see you.
الأميرة أشينا زو هنا لرؤيتك
Isn't she grounded in Shiyu's mansion?
أليست مستندة إلى قصر شييو؟
The South Prince brought her here.
أحضرها الأمير الجنوبي إلى هنا
I'm not sure why she is here.
لا أعرف لماذا هي هنا
Get her in.
ادخلها
Yes.
نعم
Greetings, Your Majesty. I'm Ashina Zhu.
تحياتي يا صاحب الجلالة، أنا أشينا تشو
I guess you came here so late
أعتقد أنك جئت إلى هنا متأخرا جدا
for the North Prince, right?
إلى الأمير الثاني، أليس كذلك؟
He'll in no case rebel.
لن متمرد في أي حال من الأحوال
Please investigate clearly, Your Majesty.
يرجى التحقيق بوضوح يا صاحب الجلالة
Why are you sure he won't rebel?
لماذا أنت متأكدة من أنه لن يتمرد؟
I haven't known him for a long time.
لم أعرفه منذ فترة طويلة
But I believe he isn't as useless or lecherous
لكنني أعتقد أنه ليس عديم الفائدة أو محبا
as people say he is.
كما يقول الناس إنه كذلك
He has helped a lot of civilians
لقد ساعد الكثير من المدنيين
without telling anyone.
دون أن يخبر أي شخص
The mission in Liuzhou is difficult.
البعثة في ليوتشو صعبة
To pacify refugees and distribute grain,
لتهدئة اللاجئين وتوزيع الحبوب
he made every effort,
بذل كل جهد
but no one praised him.
ولكن لم يثني عليه أحد
Now, the grain is gone.
الآن، فقدت الحبوب
Some people can't wait to frame him.
لا يستطيع البعض الانتظار لتأطير له
What are they really up to?
ما الذي يقومون به حقًا؟
Hoarding grain means treason.
احتجاز الحبوب يعني الخيانة
What proof do they have?
ما الدليل الذي لديها؟
When others can think of this,
عندما يستطيع الآخرون التفكير في هذا
how can the North Prince not consider it?
كيف لا يمكن لأمير الشمال النظر في الأمر؟
Even if he knew he would be suspected,
حتى لو كان يعرف أنه سيكون مشتبها به
he still distributed his own grain decisively.
وكان لا يزال يوزع حبيبته الخاصة بشكل حاسم
And he's been badly injured.
وأصيب بجروح بليغة
Even I feel aggrieved for him.
حتى أنا أشعر بالظلم بالنسبة له
Looks like someone cares for him now.
يبدو أن أحدهم يهتم به الآن
Don't worry, Princess Zhu.
لا تقلقي يا أميرة تشو
I grew up with him.
نشأت معه
I will have this case investigated
سأحقق في هذه القضية
to vindicate him.
لإثباته
What do you mean?
ماذا تعني؟
Your Majesty, please allow me to go to Liuzhou for the North Prince.
صاحب الجلالة، أرجوك اسمح لي بالذهاب إلى ليوتشو من أجل الأمير الشمالي
You get up first.
أنت انهض أولا
Please approve, Your Majesty.
موافقة، أرجوك يا صاحب الجلالة
Are you saying
هل تقصد أنك
you're going to Liuzhou personally?
هل ستذهب إلى ليوتشو شخصيا؟
Yes. He and I are engaged.
نعم، أنا وهو مخطوبان
Now, he's guilty. I can't stay out of this.
هو مذنب الآن، لا يمكنني تجنب هذا
How about you check this first?
ماذا عنك أن تتحقق من هذا أولا؟
(For the Princess's time, the North Prince would break off the engagement.)
(بوقت الأميرة، كان الأمير الشمالي سيفسخ الخطوبة)
He asked to break off the engagement with me?
طلب فسخ الارتباط معي؟
Her Grace said
قالت غريس
she would ask for a termination of engagement
سوف تطلب إنهاء الخطوبة
and then go back with me, huh?
ثم عد معي، هوه؟
Why hasn't she come out yet?
لماذا لم تخرج بعد؟
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
I told you she fooled you.
أخبرتك أنها خدعتك
I'll wait a bit longer.
سأنتظر قليلًا بعد
I'll break them up soon.
سأكسرهم قريبا
Your Highness, let's go back.
صاحب السمو، دعنا نعد
Has Her Grace come out?
هل خرجت صاحبة العريس؟
I just got to know
عرفت للتو
Her Grace left a long time ago.
غادرت غريسها منذ وقت طويل
What?
ماذا؟
I've been waiting here the whole night,
كنت أنتظر هنا طوال الليل
having nothing to eat or sleep.
لا شيء للأكل أو النوم
But she left so quickly.
لكنها غادرت بسرعة
Fine.
حسنا
She went too far, huh?
ذهبت بعيدا يا هوه؟
Don't blame me, then.
لا تلومني إذن
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
I told you Her Grace was unreliable.
أخبرتك أن صاحبة غريس لا يمكن الاعتماد عليها
Shut up. Let's go back.
اصمت، لنعد
All right.
حسنًا
(Liuzhou)
(ليوتشو)
Wake up.
استيقظ
Philanthropist Wei is here.
العمل الخيري وي هنا
- Come this way. - He's here with some grain.
- تعال إلى هنا - إنه هنا مع بعض الحبوب
It's for everybody.
هذا للجميع
Don't squeeze. You'll all have some.
لا تألق، ستتناول جميعًا بعضًا منه
- It's for everybody. - Take it.
- هذا للجميع - خذها
It's yours.
إنها لك
- It's for everybody. - Take it.
- إنها للجميع - خذها
Don't panic.
لا تستعجل في ذلك
(Luckily, some philanthropists help people.)
(لحسن الحظ، بعض الأعمال الخيرية تساعد الناس)
It's for all of you.
هذا لكم جميعا
- Thank you, Philanthropist Wei. - Here. Take it.
- شكرًا لك أيها الخيرية وي - تفضلي، خذه
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي يا صاحب السمو
Where's His Highness?
أين صاحب السمو؟
I heard he was assassinated.
سمعت أنه اغتيل
Where is he now?
أين هو الآن؟
His Highness has been searching
كان سموه يبحث
for the lost Mr. Shi on the West Hill.
السيد شي المفقود على تل الغربي
You can wait for him here.
يمكنك انتظاره هنا
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو
you can't go any farther.
لا يمكنك الذهاب إلى أبعد من ذلك
Fight.
يقاتل
Shiyu.
شيو
Yueling, what are you doing here?
يويلينغ، ماذا تفعل هنا؟
How's your injury?
كيف حال إصابتك؟
It's all right.
لا بأس
(Auspicious and Fortunate) Where are you keeping Her Grace?
(النبيل والنبيل) أين تبقي غريس؟
I was waiting the whole night.
كنت أنتظر طوال الليل
Believe it or not, I'll crush...
صدقي ذلك أم لا، سأسحق...
Crush this house.
اسكبي هذا المنزل
- Bring it on. - Come on.
- أحضره - هيا
Come on. I dare you.
هيا، أنا أجرؤ
How do you have the nerve to ask?
كيف لديك العصاب الذي تريد أن تسأله؟
Since my sister left with you,
بما أن أختي غادرت معك
she hasn't been back yet.
لم تعد بعد
- That's right. - Where are you keeping here?
- هذا صحيح - أين تحتفظ هنا؟ -
Where are you keeping Her Grace?
أين تحفظ غريستها؟
- Yeah. - Where?
- نعم - أين؟
Give Her Grace back to us!
أعيدها إلينا!
Where are you keeping her?
أين تحتفظ بها؟
Stop playing innocent.
كفّ عن العبث بالأبرياء
Give me back my future wife!
أعيدي لي زوجتي المستقبلية!
Nonsense!
هراء
- He's playing innocent. - Yeah. Give her to us.
- إنه يعزف عن الأبرياء - نعم أعطها لنا
You know what?
هل تعرف
You lost Her Highness.
لقد خسرت صاحبة السمو
We should have asked you for her.
كان يجب أن نسألك عنها
What are you yelling for?
لماذا تصرخين؟
Yeah.
نعم
How dare you even come?
كيف تجرؤ على المجيء حتى؟
Rather treasonous. How dare they talk to me like this?
رقيقة جدًا، كيف يجرؤون على التحدث إليّ هكذا؟
Shut up and hand over my sister.
اصمت وسلم أختي
- Hand her over. - Hurry.
- مهلًا إياها - بسرعة
- Hand her over! - Give back Her Highness!
- أمسكوا بها! - أعيدي صاحبة السمو!
Your Highness, let's go back.
صاحبة السمو، دعنا نعد
They outnumber us.
إنهم يفوقنا
Why would we go?
لماذا نذهب؟
I'm not scared of them.
أنا لست خائفا منهم
Your Highness, His Majesty ordered
أمير، أمر
no outsiders
لا غرباء
should approach anyone here.
يجب أن يتصل بأي شخص هنا
Please go back to your own mansion.
عد إلى قصتك رجاءً
Am I an outsider?
هل أنا خارجي؟
- Exactly.
- بالضبط
Let's go.
لنذهب
Don't go.
لا تذهب
Stay if you dare.
ابق إن كنت تجرؤ
Hey, don't go.
لا تذهبي
Get out of here.
اخرجا من هنا
Here's water. And a boat.
تفضل الماء هنا، وزورق
Let's go find Mr. Shi Xuan.
دعنا نذهب للعثور على السيد شي
All right.
حسنًا
This cave is so dark.
هذا الكهف غامق جدا
Can the missing Mr. Shi be here?
هل يمكن للسيد شي المفقود أن يكون هنا؟
My men tracked down here,
تعقب رجالي هنا
but didn't find him.
ولكن لم تجده
Be careful.
كن حذرا
Watch out!
احترس!
Why are you so badly injured?
لماذا أنت مصابة بجروح بليغة؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
Yueling,
يويلينغ
how come you're here?
كيف تأتي إلى هنا؟
Isn't my mansion sealed?
أليس قصدي مغلقًا؟
I begged His Majesty.
توسلت إلى جلالة الملك
Did you
هل قرأت المرسوم
read the decree?
المرسوم؟
Then,
إذن
we're no longer engaged.
لا داعي للخوض في الأمر
You don't need to risk your life for me.
لست مضطرةً إلى المخاطرة بحياتك من أجلي
Why did you still come?
لماذا أتيت؟
You once saved my life.
أنقذت حياتي ذات مرة
I want to save you for this once, too.
أريد أن أنقذك من أجل هذا مرة واحدة أيضًا
And you're in trouble now.
وأنت في ورطة الآن
Everyone in the Capital City says you'll rebel.
يقول الجميع في العاصمة إنك ستتمردين
How can I sit around and do nothing?
كيف يمكنني الجلوس وعدم فعل شيء؟
You don't think I'll rebel?
أنت لا تظن أنني سأتمرد؟
You won't.
لن تستمعي
Listen.
استمع
Someone's there.
شخص ما هناك
Can it be Shi Xuan?
هل يمكن أن يكون شيوان؟
But there's no more road ahead.
ولكن لا يوجد طريق بعد الآن
How can we save him?
كيف يمكننا إنقاذه؟
I have an idea.
أنا لدي فكرة
Yueling, I think I found him.
يويينغ، أعتقد أنني وجدته
Who's he?
من هو؟
Shi Xuan.
شي شيوان
Mr. Shi.
السيد شي
Mr. Shi, wake up.
السيد شي، استيقظ
Mr. Shi, it's me.
السيد شي، إنه أنا
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Let's go.
لنذهب
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو
I failed my duty
فشلت واجبي
and lost the hope for Liuzhou people.
وفقدت الأمل لشعب ليوتشو
I'm too ashamed to leave.
أنا أشعر بالخجل من المغادرة
Mr. Shi, you had a hard time.
السيد شي، لقد مررت بوقت عصيب
Can you tell me
هل يمكن أن تخبرني
how you lost the twenty thousand dan of grain?
كيف فقدت عشرين ألف طن من الحبوب؟
Who are you?
من أنت؟
You must be Mr. Shi from the Capital City, huh?
يجب أن تكون السيد شي من العاصمة، هو؟
I'm Xu Wei, the guard of the Prefect of Liuzhou.
أنا شو وي، حارس حاكم ليوتشو
At the command of the prefect,
بقيادة المحافظ
I'm here to receive you.
أنا هنا لاستقبالك
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
Xu Wei.
شو وي
It's him again.
إنه هو مرة أخرى
They not only cheated me of the grain,
لم يخونوني من الحبوب فحسب
but also tricked us up to the hill.
بل أيضا خدعنا حتى التل
When we were up here,
عندما ذهبنا إلى هنا
they revealed their true colors as bandits,
كشفوا عن لونها الحقيقي كقطاع طرق
killed all the soldiers from the Capital City,
قتل جميع الجنود من العاصمة
and imprisoned me in this cave.
وسجنني في هذا الكهف
They keep you alive
إنهم يبقيونك على قيد الحياة
to set me up, right?
لتجمعني، أليس كذلك؟
Yes.
نعم
They forced me
أجبروني على كتابة رسالة
to write a letter in my blood
كتابة رسالة بدمي
to accuse you of treason.
لاتهامك بالخيانة
Never would I give in!
لن أستسلم أبدا!
So, I've been imprisoned here all the time.
لذلك، لقد سُجنت هنا طوال الوقت
These bandits are so evil.
هؤلاء اللصوص شريرون جدًا
This is not a place to dawdle.
هذا ليس مكانا للظهور
Let's get out of here.
دعنا نخرج من هنا
Be careful.
انتبه
Slow down.
تمهّل
What's the smell?
ما هي الرائحة؟
Oh, no. Toxic smoke.
لا، الدخان السام
Let's hurry.
دعنا نسرع
Yueling.
يو لينغ
Yueling!
يول!
♪Clouds slowly float across the sky♪
♪ الغيوم تطفو ببطء عبر السماء ♪
♪Telling what is awfully bothering♪
♪ وضع ما يزعج كثيرا ♪
♪Ceaseless, love lingers and lingers♪
♪ لا يتوقف، أحب الأمور المتبقية والدائمة ♪
♪You and I both know it♪
♪ أنا وأنت نعرف ذلك ♪
♪In this world, we stay side by side♪
♪ في هذا العالم، نبقى جنبا إلى جنب ♪
♪Watching the stars rise and fall♪
♪ مشاهدة النجوم ترتفع وتنخفض ♪
♪My eyes are red from missing you♪
♪ عيني أحمر من غيابكم ♪
♪Tonight, I hope the moonlight will♪
♪ ليلة، آمل أن يكون ضوء القمر ♪
♪Kiss your eyebrows♪
♪ قبلة حاجباك ♪
♪I'll always be in love with you♪
♪ سأكون دائمًا في حبك ♪
♪Promising it'll last forever♪
♪ مؤشر على أنها ستدوم إلى الأبد ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ مع ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪Leaving a wish to be fulfilled♪
♪ إنقاذ أمنية يتعين تحقيقها ♪
♪To have joy for the rest of its life♪
♪ للفخر لبقية حياتها ♪
♪I'll stay with you for thousands of years♪
♪ سأبقى معك بآلاف السنين ♪
♪Until we grow old together♪
♪ حتى نتقدم في السن معا ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ كما ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪When I look back, you whisper♪
♪ عندما أنظر إلى الوراء، أنت أتذمر ♪
♪Then I wake up from the dream♪
♪ إذن أستيقظ من الحلم ♪
♪Like how we met for the first time♪
♪ مثل كيفية التقينا للمرة الأولى ♪